marchforbabies.org 2010-12-05

# March of Dimes Privacy Policy & Your Privacy Rights - March of Dimes

Effective December 5, 2005

Privacy Policy Table of Contents 

Introduction  
Contact Information, Accessing and Correcting Your Personal Information  
The Information We Collect and How We Use It  
Sharing Your Information with Third Parties  
Opting out of Future Communications  
Our Commitment to Data Security  
Your Child's Privacy  
Privacy Policies for Specific Features  
  \- Genetics & Your Practice  
  \- Perinatal Nursing Education  
  \- Online Fundraising Tool  
  \- Every Baby Has A Story  
Your Privacy Rights Under California Law

**  
Introduction**  
The mission of March of Dimes is to improve the health of babies by preventing birth defects, premature birth and infant mortality. The March of Dimes web site provides information, resources, referrals and data intended to assist the public in having healthy pregnancies and healthy births. The web site also provides information for health care professionals and offers opportunities for volunteering in March of Dimes fundraising events. 

This Privacy Policy applies to all of our on-line activities including  the **_Genetics & Your Practice®,_** Perinatal Nursing Education, Every Baby Has a Story, and Online Fundraising Tool sites, however specific information pertaining only to the Privacy Policies of these sites is described in detail in separate sections within this Policy.

**Contact Information, Accessing and Correcting Your Personal Information**  
If you have any questions about this Policy or you wish to review or correct your personal information or the personal information of your child that we may have on file, you may contact us by U.S. mail, e-mail or telephone at the addresses and numbers listed below.

March of Dimes  
Attn: Privacy Manager   
1275 Mamaroneck Avenue  
White Plains, NY 10605

e-mail: [donorservice@marchofdimes.com](mailto:donorservice@marchofdimes.com)

Telephone: 1-888-MODIMES.  

**Our Commitment to Privacy**  
We at March of Dimes recognize the importance of protecting your privacy. The purpose of this notice is to explain the practices and procedures we implement to protect your personal information, the way we use this information, and the choices you can make regarding our of your personal information. This notice can be accessed by clicking on a “Privacy” link on every page of our web site.  March of Dimes is committed to protecting your privacy and will honor this Policy. 

**_Changes to this Policy_**  
March of Dimes reserves the right to change this policy at any time. To better serve you and your concerns about your privacy, we will notify you of any changes to this Policy by posting a notice prominently on the main page of our web site (<http://www.marchofdimes.com/>) indicating that there has been a change or update to the Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read this Policy. 

**The Information We Collect and How We Use It  
** You may browse the March of Dimes web site without submitting personal information.   However, if you choose to participate in any of our online activities, you will asked for applicable personal data such as your name, gender, postal address, email address, phone number, fax number and payment information . The purpose of collecting such data is to respond to specific questions, to register you for March for BabiesSM  and other events that have online registration, to honor requests for brochures or newsletters or to process payments and donations made online.  March of Dimes also uses this personal information to advise users of new online materials, activities, and events and to provide users with the opportunity to contribute to local and national programs and research initiatives. 

March of Dimes also collects personal information offline from volunteers, donors and event participants. Such information may include name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, age, etc. The information is collected through offline registration forms, telemarketing appeals and postal appeals.  Personal information such as name, address, and payment history may be collected and forwarded to March of Dimes Chapters as well as the March of Dimes National Office.  March of Dimes uses this personal information to inform volunteers and donors of new materials, activities and events with the opportunity to contribute to local and national programs and research initiatives.

**_Personal Health-Related Information_**  
Personal information included in specific questions submitted to the _Pregnancy & Newborn Health Education Center®_ of March of Dimes via “Ask Us Now” or “Info Now” is used solely to enable March of Dimes professionals to best answer questions posed by the user. All other information entered on this site is used for aggregate demographic analysis only and no personally identifiable information is included in these analyses. Records regarding the nature of individual inquiries to the _Pregnancy & Newborn Health Education Center_ are used to create aggregate reports for internal use only and are purged after one calendar year from the date of inquiry.   Personally identifiable information and any information about your health submitted to the _Pregnancy & Newborn Health Education Center_ from “Info Now” and “Ask Now” is only accessed by March of Dimes employees on a “need to know” basis, never shared with any other March of Dimes department and is used only to respond to the question you have posted. 

**_Email A Friend_**  
In order to further our mission and inform you about what you can do to prevent birth defects and have a healthy pregnancy, we offer a feature on our web site that enables you to email the article or fact sheet you are viewing to a friend. This feature requires that you enter your name and email address and the name and email address of the recipient.  March of Dimes stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

**_Payment Information_**  
Payment information, such as credit card number and expiration date, is entered when making a donation or paying for a professional education course. The March of Dimes uses PayPal and Verisign as third-party intermediaries to process your online donations and payments. Your credit card information is encrypted when submitted to the processor and transmitted over a secure connection between your computer and our server using Secure Socket Layers (SSL), the industry standard, to ensure protection of your private information. This sensitive personal information is not shared with third parties other than the processor and is stored by March of Dimes for verification purposes or for recurring donations that you have authorized.

**_Cookies, Gifs, Logs_**

Cookies are small text files that a website can place on a visitor’s computer hard drive to recognize repeat visitors, to facilitate a visitor’s use of the site and to track a visitor’s access to and use of the site.

March of Dimes uses cookies to collect demographic data that help us better advertise our mission, programs and events to potential visitors and to improve the functionality of the website and the experience for those who use our site. We receive data that include the IP addresses, browser types, date/time stamp, donations and sign-up information of visitors to our site.   
In addition, March of Dimes uses cookies to allow us to track which other websites have linked visitors to our site, what pages of our site are used by and are of interest to those visitors, and to link to information those visitors provide to the March of Dimes when they donate or sign up to take part in our programs and events   
Cookies are used in the Genetics & Your Practice and the Perinatal Nursing Education sites in order to remember the user’s name and your course progress. Sites containing other programs run by the March of Dimes may contain information as to how cookies are used on those sites.  

**_March of Dimes Store and Product Promotions_**  
The March of Dimes store and product promotions are operated on external sites owned by third parties. When you click on a link to the March of Dimes store or to a production promotion, you are leaving marchofdimes.com and entering the site of a third party.  Please click on the “Privacy Policy” link at the bottom of the store web site to view the privacy policy followed by our third party providers.  March of Dimes may receive product sales reports that contain your personal information such as name, quantity ordered, e-mail address and postal address.   This information is used for internal reporting and monitoring purposes only.  This information is not distributed outside of the March of Dimes to any other parties.  March of Dimes never receives credit card numbers from third party sites. 

**_Sharing Your Information with Third Parties  
_** March of Dimes never shares your e-mail addresses with third parties without your consent. Personal information collected from our donation pages (including Donate Now, Banding Together, On-Line Fundraising Tools, March for BabiesSM) is never shared with third parties. However, March of Dimes reserves the right to rent or exchange the names and postal addresses of donors or volunteers (Mothers March for example)who have sent a donation to the March of Dimes via postal mail or as a result of telemarketing request.  We rent or exchange names and postal addresses as a way of raising funds to support important functions and services. This is the only circumstance in which personal information (name and address only) is released to third parties and the only information released. Such third parties may include March of Dimes event sponsors and other non-profit and commercial companies. Mailers are carefully screened and must comply with use policies established by March of Dimes.  For a copy of March of Dimes usage policy please contact the Privacy Manager at the address listed at the top of this Privacy Policy. **If you would like to opt-out of the list rental and exchange program you may write to us at March of Dimes, c/o CPI, 111 Venure Drive, Dover NH 03820 or e-mail us at**[ **donorservice@marchofdimes.com**](mailto:donorservice@marchofdimes.com) **.   As a member of the Direct Marketing Association (DMA), March of Dimes complies and uses Direct Marketing Association Preference Service.  You can add your name to this file by visiting the DMA website located at **[**http://www.dmaconsumers.org**](http://www.dmaconsumers.org/) **.**

If you are a _California resident_ , please click here to view “Your Privacy Rights” under California law.

**_Public Forums_**  
The March of Dimes advises users that personal information posted on “Share Your Story” is accessible to the public. By posting information on this site, you may receive unsolicited messages from third parties unrelated to the March of Dimes. The March of Dimes monitors these sites, however it remains the responsibility of the site visitor to use his/her best judgment in choosing the information he/she will post.

**_Opting-Out of Future March of Dimes Communications_**  
You may opt out of March of Dimes communications at any time by contacting [donorservice@marchofdimes.com](mailto:donorservice@marchofdimes.com).  
March of Dimes reserves the right to acknowledge your donation.  If you have subscribed to any March of Dimes newsletter, you may unsubscribe by following the instructions in the email containing the newsletter.  You may also remove yourself from the March of Dimes e-mail list by contacting us via email at: [donorservice@marchofdimes.com](mailto:donorservice@marchofdimes.com). Your email address is never shared with third parties without your express consent.

You may also notify us that you choose to opt-out of all communications from the March of Dimes by completing and sending the form available in this Privacy Policy. Please send us your name, phone number, and email and postal addresses and check off the box indicating that you would like to opt-out of all communications from the March of Dimes.

**_California Residents_**  
The special notice for California residents per _California Privacy Law (SB27): Exchanging, Renting, Reselling Personal Information_ , can be accessed at "Your Privacy Rights under California Law."

**Our Commitment to Data Security**  
March of Dimes implements physical, electronic and managerial procedures to ensure that your personal information is protected at all times. Our servers are housed in an off-site, secured co-location facility. Employee access to personal information is strictly on a need to know basis. All employees are made aware of the Privacy Policy and of any updates or changes to it. Employees are reminded of the importance of protecting the privacy of our donors and Internet site users. 

**Your Child's Privacy**  
We may collect your child’s personal information such as name, e-mail address, and postal address in order to register him or her in March of Dimes activities such as  the Youth Times newsletter or our annual  March for BabiesSM event.

Your child’s personal information is subject to all of the terms of this privacy policy.  If you do not wish your child to participate in March of Dimes activities, please contact [donorservice@marchofdimes.com](mailto:donorservice@marchofdimes.com).

**Privacy Policies for Special MarchofDimes.com Features**

**_Genetics& Your Practice®_**  
The Genetics & Your Practice (“G&YP”) site on the March of Dimes main web site is designed for professionals working in the primary care setting and has custom modules for preconception/ prenatal; infants/children; and adolescents/adults. This site allows you to register for courses for which you can receive continuing education credits. In order for you to obtain maximum benefit from this web site and obtain continuing education credits, it is necessary for you to register and create your own personal account by entering personally identifiable information on the registration page. 

**_Registration_**  
The information collected through the registration process is analyzed in the aggregate for internal use and will not be submitted to third parties without your permission. Some of the information that is requested on the registration page is optional. However, you are required to submit the following information to the March of Dimes: username, state, country, occupation, email address and how you heard about the site. You are also required to create a password that will enable you to log in and access your own personal account on the G&YP site. This information will not be forwarded to any third party without your permission unless you are applying for continuing professional education credit.

You will be asked whether you would like to hear from the March of Dimes regarding issues relevant to G&YP and for news alerts, progress reports and promotions to benefit the March of Dimes. You may opt-out of these communications at any time by clicking on “My Account” on the main G&YP page. 

You may review and correct your personal information at any time by clicking on “My Account” on the main G&YP page.

**_Continuing Professional Education_**  
By providing your personal information for continuing education credit, you are granting us permission to forward it to the professional education provider, Swedish Medical Center, and any other accrediting organizations that require it. Your personal information will be used to generate your certificate of completion and for aggregate reporting. Information forwarded to the professional education provider or any other accrediting authority will be subject to their individual privacy policies. 

**_Site Evaluations_**  
If you are seeking a Continuing Medical Education (“CME”) credit, you will be required to complete a pre-test and post-test to gauge your knowledge prior to (pre-test) and after (post-test) participation in the case study.  You must also complete the case study, CME Evaluation survey and a CME registration form. Completing the pre-test, post-test, CME evaluation survey and CME registration are not required if you are not seeking to obtain CME credits. The March of Dimes does not link information obtained from the pre- and post-tests to personal identifiers, this information is analyzed for the purpose of compiling aggregate statistics only.  Results from the evaluations may be published in peer review journals. You will not be contacted by us unless you opt in to the follow up evaluation.

**_Tracking_**  
We use your account information to track your personal preferences and progress on the G&YP web site. Using cookies, information from the web site is stored on our servers to enable you to personalize the site to your specification. In addition, we track and record your progress through the site in order to help you remember which parts of the site you have visited and to record your attempts at the various tests throughout the site. We also use the tracking system to measure how effective the content is by recording your responses to questions and interactions throughout the site. 

**_Security_**  
Personal information collected on the G&YP web site is secured by current, reasonable industry standards. Your user name and password are encrypted. We use SSL technology, the industry standard, for online donations and your credit card account information is encrypted when submitted for processing and  verification. 

**_Contact Us for Questions_**  
For questions about this policy please contact [gyponline@marchofdimes.com](mailto:gyponline@marchofdimes.com)  

**Perinatal Nursing Education**  
The Perinatal Nursing Education (“PNE”) site is designed to provide continuing education for perinatal nurses. This site allows you to create a personal account and register for continuing education credits. In order for you to obtain maximum benefit from this web site and obtain continuing education credits, it is necessary for you to register and create your own personal account by entering personally identifiable information on the registration page. 

**_Registration_**  
The information collected through the registration process is analyzed in the aggregate for internal use and will not be submitted to third parties without your permission. Some of the information that is requested on the registration page is optional. However, you are required to submit the following information to the March of Dimes: username, name, email address, postal address and occupation. You are also required to create a password that will enable you to log in and access your own personal account on the PNE site. This information will not be forwarded to any third party without your permission.

You will be asked whether you would like to hear from the March of Dimes regarding issues relevant to PNE and for news alerts, progress reports and promotions to benefit the March of Dimes. You may opt-out of these communications at any time by clicking on “My Account” on the main PNE page. 

You may review and correct your personal information at any time by clicking on “My Account” on the main PNE page.

**_Continuing Professional Education_**  
Your personal information will be used for aggregate reporting and to generate your certificate of completion. If you use a token code purchased by someone else to complete the course, that person will have access to the following information: whether or not you used the code, your email address, and whether your passed or failed the continuing education test.

**_Site Evaluations_**  
You may choose to opt-in or opt-out of the evaluation of the PNE site, pre-tests and post-tests. Pre-test and post-tests gauge your knowledge prior to (pre-test) and after (post-test) participation in the module. The March of Dimes does not link information obtained from the pre- and post-tests to personal identifiers, this information is analyzed for the purpose of compiling aggregate statistics only. 

**_Tracking_**  
We use your account information to track your personal preferences and progress on the PNE web site. Using cookies, information from the web site is stored on our serves to enable you to personalize the site to your specification. In addition, we track and record your progress through the site in order to help you remember which parts of the site you have visited and to record your attempts at the various tests throughout the site. We also use the tracking system to measure how effective the content is by recording your responses to questions and interactions throughout the site. 

**_Security_**  
Personal information collected on the PNE web site is secured by current, reasonable industry standards. Your user name and password are encrypted. We use SSL technology, the industry standard, for online donations and your credit card account information is encrypted when submitted for processing and  verification. 

**_Contact Us for Questions_**  
For questions about this policy, please contact [profedu@marchofdimes.com](mailto:profedu@marchofdimes.com)  

**Online Fundraising Tool (March for Babies SM, Bikes for Babies, BandingTogether®, and Jail & Bail)**

The Online Fundraising Tool is intended to help users maximize their fundraising efforts; therefore, the March of Dimes has made every effort to provide an application that is safe and secure.

**_Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information.  _** The March of Dimes does not retain names, addresses and email addresses of persons invited to use the Online Fundraising Tool system but who do not actually participate by creating pages or donating funds.   For persons who do participate, their personal information is retained by the March of Dimes National Office and by the local March of Dimes Chapter for future correspondence.  Users and the participants that they recruit may opt-out of communications with March of Dimes according to the procedures outlined in this Privacy Policy.

**Every Baby Has a Story™**

When you visit the _Every Baby Has a Story_ web site, you will have the opportunity to create multimedia scrapbooks, or “scrapblogs” that you can upload onto the _Every Baby Has a Story_ web site. In order to register and use this service, you will need to provide your email and other personal information.  The _Every Baby Has a Story_ web site may, from time to time, offer other events and services that also require you to provide some form of personal information.  The information we collect and how we use that information is contained in separate Privacy Policies or Notices that are posted and are available on the _Every Baby Has a Story_ web site before you provide your personal information.

**Your Privacy Rights Under California Law**  
Websites owned by organizations that operate in California must comply with the privacy practices outlined in California privacy bill S.B.27 pertaining to the collection and use of personal information in direct marketing activities. 

As discussed throughout this Policy, March of Dimes honors your requests concerning your own personal information as it pertains to online and postal, and telemarketing communications as well as list rentals and exchanges. 

If you prefer not to participate in our list rental and exchange program, receive email communications or postal mail or telephone calls from the March of Dimes, please follow the links below to opt-out from participation. Please select the appropriate links below.

[I would like to opt-out of your list rental and exchange program.](http://www.marchofdimes.com/aboutus/17879.asp)  
[I would like to request a disclosure of your list rental and exchange practices.](http://www.marchofdimes.com/aboutus/17879.asp)
